<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datascience on Alternative Stats</title>
    <link>https://alternative-stats.netlify.com/tags/datascience.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datascience on Alternative Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Thomas Speidel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/datascience.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Biostatistics and Policing: An Example of Application and the Role of Statistical Literacy in Today&#39;s Organizations</title>
      <link>https://alternative-stats.netlify.com/post/biostatistics-and-policing-an-example-of-application-and-the-role-of-statistical-literacy-in-today-s-organizations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alternative-stats.netlify.com/post/biostatistics-and-policing-an-example-of-application-and-the-role-of-statistical-literacy-in-today-s-organizations.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best past of my job is that, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2000/07/28/us/john-tukey-85-statistician-coined-the-word-software.html?mcubz=0&#34;&gt;John Tukey&lt;/a&gt; famously said, &lt;strong&gt;I get to play in everyone’ sandbox&lt;/strong&gt;. It also brings positive unintended ramifications: we get to cross-pollinate fields. Perhaps, none of this is clearer than how biostatistics helps with &lt;a href=&#34;http://press.anu.edu.au/node/162/download&#34;&gt;policing serious crime in Australia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;policing_resious_crime.jpg&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the authors, Robyn Attewell, writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my statistical perspective is grounded in biostatistics which is the application of statistics in the study of disease and, more generally, the human condition. This is an area in which statistical principles have been well accepted and applied. I do not mean that all doctors know what a chi-square test is or could interpret a logistic regression. However, advances in knowledge in epidemiology and the treatment of disease have occurred through research which has been undertaken with the application of sound statistical methodology. The evidence base for prevention and treatment of disease has moved from personal experience and chronicles of case histories to global randomised controlled trials, longitudinal cohort studies and meta-analyses. The movement within the fields of public health and medicine towards a quantitative evidence base is so strong that the pharmaceutical industry, for example, is very highly regulated. New drug treatments are not able to be registered or receive government subsidy unless supported by a structured compilation of efficacy and safety data. It has to be proven beyond reasonable doubt that new medications work and their positive impact on the target disease outweighs any negatives through adverse side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attewell’s experience mirrors mine (and I bet, that of many other statisticians), having too worked in &lt;a href=&#34;http://epi-research.org/&#34;&gt;biostatistics&lt;/a&gt; for many years and later migrated into energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps not as homogeneous as in other fields - there are indeed isolated pockets of statistical excellence in the energy industry - I routinely come across areas that not only lack statistical principles, but where I perceive a mistrust in something that’s perceived as new and unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we over-simplify the statistical methods so that they can be grasped by our audience at the cost of being woefully wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, statistics and data science aren’t easy and thinking probabilistically is admittedly hard. This presents a challenge for the statistician or the data scientist: do we over-simplify the statistical methods so that they can be grasped by our audience at the cost of being woefully wrong? Do we, instead engage in the daunting task of educating our audience in statistical principles? Or shall we present the finding as unquestionable dogma … hey, just trust the fancy math?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics is hard. Multiple regression is hard. Figuring out the appropriate denominator is hard. These errors aren’t so elementary. Andrew Gelman, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stephensenn?lang=en&#34;&gt;Stephen John Senn&lt;/a&gt; captures parts of this dilemma when he writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the need for clear results cannot be cited as grounds for only ever using the simplest of techniques. Statistics is no different from other sciences in this respect. Just as we cannot insist that chemist determine pH using litmus paper because that is what the non-chemist remembers from school, so we cannot insist that statisticians restrict themselves to a simple T-test because this was state of the art in 1908.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our colleagues who focus on &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;ML&lt;/strong&gt;) face similar dilemmas, perhaps even more so, given that ML methods tend to be uninterpretable &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/can-we-open-the-black-box-of-ai-1.20731&#34;&gt;black-boxes&lt;/a&gt;. Two recent papers that touch on this subjects are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kdd.org/kdd2016/papers/files/rfp0573-ribeiroA.pdf&#34;&gt;Ribeiro&lt;/a&gt; et al. and &lt;a href=&#34;http://opim.wharton.upenn.edu/risk/library/WPAF201410-AlgorthimAversion-Dietvorst-Simmons-Massey.pdf&#34;&gt;Dietvorst&lt;/a&gt; et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ribeiro.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;dietvorst.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no question in my mind that we need to increase the level of statistical literacy. However, the job of filling the gap left by an educational system that has historically failed to teach statistics cannot be entirely left in the hands of applied statisticians and data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We teach our children the mathematics of certainty - geometry and trigonometry- but not the mathematics of uncertainty, statistical thinking. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerd_Gigerenzer&#34;&gt;Gert Gigerenzer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-to-do&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see very encouraging signs in recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science,_technology,_engineering,_and_mathematics&#34;&gt;STEM&lt;/a&gt; graduates, anecdotally at least, since I see them much better prepared to recognize statistical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the issue remains for those who have not had a chance to upgrade their skills: &lt;strong&gt;how then, do we increase data and statistical literacy in the current leaders and decision makers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;vendors-consultants-and-hype-make-things-a-lot-harder&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vendors, Consultants (and Hype) Make Things a Lot Harder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the practicing statistician and data scientist, vendors and consultants are a double edge sword. On one hands they help by bringing to light how statistics, ML (or whatever catchy word du jour is in vogue) can help organizations; because they have a more direct communication channel with upper management, the message makes it to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, they have little vested interests in educating, let alone provide a fair view of the landscape. And in the long run, this is damaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, none of this damage is clearer than what’s happening with IBM Watson in health care where the “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/607965/a-reality-check-for-ibms-ai-ambitions/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;unrealistic timelines or promises&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” are now becoming obvious and, perhaps, backfiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not too worried about health care where the unrealistic claims are usually met with a dismissive shrug, precisely because, as Attewel writes, statistical principles have been well accepted and applied in that field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But think about areas where statistical principles are not nearly as pervasive. Lack of statistical literacy, means our defense mechanism is unprepared. Instead, the receiver has to rely on faulty heuristics and anecdotes such as: “&lt;em&gt;I heard SmartCo is using this tool, so it must be good&lt;/em&gt;” with little science to back them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time, the organization realizes those promises never materialized, the claims were unrealistic, and preconceived notions are re-inforced after a brief hiatus of hope. In a field where there are no certain truths, it’s easy to throw away the baby with the bathwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;summary&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Science and Statistics, including more specialized branches, such as biostatistics, have wide applicability in many analytical problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical literacy and critical thinking present a gap that is easily exploited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to do a better job at educating people unfamiliar with data science and statistics, but this cannot be left entirely in the hands of the practitioner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science in the Organization: Things I Learned in 2016</title>
      <link>https://alternative-stats.netlify.com/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alternative-stats.netlify.com/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;user-2016&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;useR! 2016&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;stanford.jpg&#34; /&gt; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://user2016.org/&#34;&gt;useR! conference&lt;/a&gt; in Stanford was awesome. Never did I expect to see so many participants (read: data geeks) and high level &lt;a href=&#34;http://user2016.org/#sponsors&#34;&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;. For what was a little known language that’s been around in one form or another since the late seventies, this is quite amazing. Some memorable talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;People are doing really amazing things with &lt;strong&gt;Shiny&lt;/strong&gt;. I was amazed at the pervasiveness of Shiny at &lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conference/useR2016/RServer-Operationalizing-R-at-Electronic-Arts&#34;&gt;EA Games&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;R’s superhero &lt;strong&gt;Hadley Whickham&lt;/strong&gt;, never takes a break. His idea is to create a “&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conference/useR2016/Towards-a-grammar-of-interactive-graphics&#34;&gt;pit of success&lt;/a&gt;” by having a uniform approach to import, tidy, transform, visualize, model and communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniela Witten methodology on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conference/useR2016/Flexible-and-Interpretable-Regression-Using-Convex-Penalties&#34;&gt;interpretable regression using convex penalties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: as I see it, it’s an attempt to do the least damage when people want simple interpretation of non-linear coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tal Galili gave a great presentation on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conference/useR2016/Heatmaps-in-R-Overview-and-best-practices&#34;&gt;heatmaps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in R&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rick Beckett on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/useR-international-R-User-conference/useR2016/Forty-years-of-S&#34;&gt;40 years of S&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was fascinating: now I understand why the assignment operator in R is &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; (hint: jump to 0:29:00). We also learned that S and UNIX were two Bell Labs projects that grew together. Ironic how both took a while to be picked up and both grew into massively popular platforms (Linux, R).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-driven-decisions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Data-Driven Decisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-time data practitioner, I don’t get the cult-like infatuation with the term “data-driven” decisions (see here, here or here). Really folks: in the best case scenario we go from: data to evidence to decisions. If we want to go from data to decisions, hope for the best, because science may not back you up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In health research, the term “data driven” has negative connotations. Instead, we have a much more scientifically sound **[evidence-based]*(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evidence-based_medicine)*&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evidence-based_medicine)*&lt;/a&gt; approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;evidence_based.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study suggests that &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/2593252&#34;&gt;women make better doctors than men&lt;/a&gt; (also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2016/12/female-doctors-superiority/511034/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nbcnews.com/health/health-news/female-doctors-outperform-male-doctors-according-study-n697876&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://stream.org/whos-better-playing-doctor-boys-girls/&#34;&gt;many problems&lt;/a&gt; with this study. But it got me thinking of a way to explain how “data driven” can be dangerous: if women are better doctor because they treated many fewer patients than men and, therefore, had more time to spend with patients, then, the data-driven decision of having more women doctors won’t lead to improved health outcomes. But, hey, it’s “data driven”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This echos well-known statistician &lt;a href=&#34;http://vkc.mc.vanderbilt.edu/people/harrell-frank&#34;&gt;Frank Harrell&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the data to guide the data analysis is almost as dangerous as not doing so“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ethics-ethics-ethics&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ethics, Ethics, Ethics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;ethics.jpg&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ties between &lt;strong&gt;statistics and ethics&lt;/strong&gt; are well known (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/3564481?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Nearly every PhD biostatistician I know has sat on an ethics board at some points in their careers. Now, it seems that the broader field of &lt;strong&gt;Data Science is starting to pay attention to the ethical implications of their work&lt;/strong&gt;. A few key events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great article on ProPublica on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing&#34;&gt;predictive sentencing&lt;/a&gt; in the US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More and more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edx.org/course/data-science-ethics-michiganx-ds101x-1&#34;&gt;courses&lt;/a&gt; on ethics in data science are starting to emerge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cathy O’Neal’s book “&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/roots-of-unity/review-weapons-of-math-destruction/&#34;&gt;Weapon of Math Destruction: How Big Data Increases Inequality and Threatens Democracy&lt;/a&gt;” is on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/0weW8WA&#34;&gt;Amazon wish list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google provides one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.google.com/bigpicture/attacking-discrimination-in-ml/&#34;&gt;best explanations&lt;/a&gt; I have seen on the difficulty of making fair decisions. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.statschat.org.nz/2017/01/01/kinds-of-fairness-worth-working-for/&#34;&gt;Thomas Lumley&lt;/a&gt; writes: “&lt;strong&gt;You have to decide what summary of the difference you care about, because you can’t make them all the same&lt;/strong&gt;. This is old news in medical diagnostics, but appears not to have been considered in some other areas”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;unicorns&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Unicorns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/736x/9d/0e/e6/9d0ee6c0049e088172590e0d81b1684c--polygon-art-diy-paper.jpg&#34; /&gt; This year has confirmed that Data Science is a &lt;strong&gt;wide and broad field&lt;/strong&gt;, just like Medicine, Law or Engineering: many flavours, many specializations. Sorry folks, &lt;strong&gt;unicorns who are specialist in everything do not exist&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like hospitals do not hire a family physicians and expect them to do the work of 100 specialists, just like we don’t hire a criminal lawyer when we need a tax lawyer, organizations cannot expect to hire one data scientist generalist and do the work of 100 specialists. &lt;a href=&#34;http://drewconway.com/zia/2013/7/18/warning-do-not-feed-the-wildebeests&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s not fall into the trap of judging a Data Scientist by the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical or algorithmic sophistication&lt;/strong&gt; of their arsenals. In the words of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Kahneman&#34;&gt;Kahneman&lt;/a&gt;, we would be substituting a question which we cannot answer with a different one which we can answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;automation-model-factories&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Automation &amp;amp; Model Factories&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;automation.png&#34; /&gt; Automation is really misunderstood. Really. I was pointed to &lt;strong&gt;Tom Davenport’s&lt;/strong&gt; article on “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/pulse/move-your-analytics-operation-from-artisanal-tom-davenport?trk=hp-feed-article-title-like&#34;&gt;Autonomous Analytics&lt;/a&gt;” and the concept of &lt;strong&gt;model factory&lt;/strong&gt; as described in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNfsnv9gjrU&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great article and agree with pretty much everything. It’s what it &lt;strong&gt;does not say&lt;/strong&gt; that concerns me. I commented in Tom’s article, but briefly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everything is worth automating (e.g. single points decisions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everything is automatable (causal models, explanatory models, exploratory analysis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation is more of an IT problem than a Data Science one (see &lt;strong&gt;Diego Kuonen’s&lt;/strong&gt; fantastic slides on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/kuonen/demystifying-big-data-data-science-and-statistics-along-with-machine-intelligence-and-learning&#34;&gt;Demystifying Big Data, Data Science and Statistics&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;em&gt;Which means it is the last mile of a repetitive insight generation process the mechanisms of which are well understood and that applies to a well understood class of problems (predictive)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-wrangling&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Data Wrangling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;data_wrangling.jpg&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/08/18/technology/for-big-data-scientists-hurdle-to-insights-is-janitor-work.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;Data munging/carpentry/wrangling&lt;/a&gt;, you know, that tedious, time consuming work that &lt;strong&gt;takes some 80% of a data scientist’s time&lt;/strong&gt; is (still) not given enough credit by evangelists, vendors, consultants and speakers. Not sexy? Sure, but it’s a reality we must face nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, is hardly automatable (see above) and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/ideas/why-data-preparation-frameworks-rely-on-human-in-the-loop-systems&#34;&gt;human-in-the-loop&lt;/a&gt; provides myriads of necessary context and judgement calls that machines cannot make. I bet this has caused a lot of misunderstanding in organizations: “&lt;em&gt;What? Are you trying to tell me we spent $100K for that fancy analytics software and it’s useless?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;analytical-maturity&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analytical Maturity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://xolotl.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/7159036564_ec69766fe7_o.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the keywords and verbiage used by organizations to advertise their data related jobs are any indication of their &lt;strong&gt;analytical maturity&lt;/strong&gt;, there are promising signs! I work in the energy sector, not Silicon Valley, which means it takes a little while for us to pick up on technological or scientific innovations. For the past four years, I received weekly job alerts and, anecdotally, I can say that the expectations, clarity and keywords of the ad have improved significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;analytics-podcasts&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analytics Podcasts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.licdn.com/mpr/mpr/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAh-AAAAJGMxOWY3NzViLWEwYmItNDBkOS1iNDc3LTkyYTA5OGFmYjA4ZQ.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of really good analytics podcasts has grown significantly, to the point I can barely keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcloud.com/nssd-podcast&#34;&gt;Not So Standard Deviation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataskeptic.com/&#34;&gt;The Data Skeptic Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://partiallyderivative.com/&#34;&gt;Partially Derivative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://datastori.es/&#34;&gt;Data Stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/topics/oreilly-data-show-podcast&#34;&gt;O’Reilly Data Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thetalkingmachines.com/&#34;&gt;Talking Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not So Standard Deviations and O’Reilly Data Show are great detox if you are subject to a considerable amount of timeshare-sque-like products and hyperbolic claims by vendors or consultants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
