<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alternative Stats</title>
    <link>/post.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alternative Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Thomas Speidel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science in the Organization: Things I Learned in 2016</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;user-2016&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;useR! 2016&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.licdn.com/mpr/mpr/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAlBAAAAJGVhNDBmODhjLTQ2ZDQtNGU2OS1iMjA4LWMwMWI4ZjE4MmUxMw.jpg&#34; /&gt; The useR! conference in Stanford was awesome. Never did I expect to see so many participants (read: data geeks) and high level sponsors. For what was a little known language that’s been around in one form or another since the late seventies, this is quite amazing. Some memorable talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are doing really amazing things with Shiny. I was amazed at the pervasiveness of Shiny at EA Games. R’s superhero Hadley Whickham, never takes a break. His idea is to create a “pit of success” by having a uniform approach to import, tidy, transform, visualize, model and communicate. Daniela Witten methodology on interpretable regression using convex penalties: as I see it, it’s an attempt to do the least damage when people want simple interpretation of non-linear coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tal Galili gave a great presentation on heatmaps in R Rick Beckett on 40 years of S was fascinating: now I understand why the assignment operator in R is &amp;lt;- (hint: jump to 0:29:00). We also learned that S and UNIX were two Bell Labs projects that grew together. Ironic how both took a while to be picked up and both grew into massively popular platforms (Linux, R).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-driven-decisions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Data-Driven Decisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-time data practitioner, I don’t get the cult-like infatuation with the term “data-driven” decisions (see here, here or here). Really folks: in the best case scenario we go from: data to evidence to decisions. If we want to go from data to decisions, hope for the best, because science may not back you up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the data to guide the data analysis is almost as dangerous as not doing so In health research, the term “data driven” has negative connotations. Instead, we have a much more scientifically sound evidence-based approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study suggests that women make better doctors than men (also here and here). There are many problems with this study. But it got me thinking of a way to explain how “data driven” can be dangerous: if women are better doctor because they treated many fewer patients than men and, therefore, had more time to spend with patients, then, the data-driven decision of having more women doctors won’t lead to improved health outcomes. But, hey, it’s “data driven”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This echos well-known statistician Frank Harrell: “Using the data to guide the data analysis is almost as dangerous as not doing so”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ethics-ethics-ethics&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ethics, Ethics, Ethics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ties between statistics and ethics are well known (see here). Nearly every PhD biostatistician I know has sat on an ethics board at some points in their careers. Now, it seems that the broader field of Data Science is starting to pay attention to the ethical implications of their work. A few key events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great article on ProPublica on predictive sentences in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More and more courses on ethics in data science are starting to emerge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cathy O’Neal’s book “Weapon of Math Destruction: How Big Data Increases Inequality and Threatens Democracy” is on my Amazon wish list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google provides one of the best explanations I have seen on the difficulty of making fair decisions. As Thomas Lumley writes: “You have to decide what summary of the difference you care about, because you can’t make them all the same. This is old news in medical diagnostics, but appears not to have been considered in some other areas”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;unicorns&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Unicorns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has confirmed that Data Science is a wide and broad field, just like Medicine, Law or Engineering: many flavours, many specializations. Sorry folks, unicorns who are specialist in everything do not exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like hospitals do not hire a family physicians and expect them to do the work of 100 specialists, just like we don’t hire a criminal lawyer when we need a tax lawyer, organizations cannot expect to hire one data scientist generalist and do the work of 100 specialists. Diversity is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s not fall into the trap of judging a Data Scientist by the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical or algorithmic sophistication&lt;/strong&gt; of their arsenals. In the words of Kahneman, we would be substituting a question which we cannot answer with another one which we can answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;automation-model-factories&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Automation &amp;amp; Model Factories&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automation is really misunderstood. Really. I was pointed to Tom Davenport’s article on “Autonomous Analytics” and the concept of model factory as described in this video. It’s a great article and agree with pretty much everything. It’s what it does not say that concerns me. I commented in Tom’s article, but briefly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everything is worth automating (e.g. single points decisions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everything is automatable (causal models, explanatory models, exploratory analysis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation is more of an IT problem than a Data Science one (see Diego Kuonen’s fantastic slides on Demystifying Big Data, Data Science and Statistics). Which means it is the last mile of a repetitive insight generation process the mechanisms of which are well understood and that applies to a well understood class of problems (predictive).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;data-wrangling&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Data Wrangling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data munging/carpentry/wrangling, you know, that tedious, time consuming work that takes some 80% of a data scientist’s time is (still) not given enough credit by evangelists, vendors, consultants and speakers. Not sexy? Sure, but it’s a reality we must face nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, is hardly automatable (see above) and the human-in-the-loop provides myriads of necessary context and judgement calls that machines cannot make. I bet this has caused a lot of misunderstanding in organizations: “What? Are you trying to tell me we spent $100K for that fancy analytics software and it’s useless?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;analytical-maturity&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analytical Maturity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the keywords and verbiage used by organizations to advertise their data related jobs are any indication of their analytical maturity, there are promising signs! I work in the energy sector, not Silicon Valley, which means it takes a little while for us to pick up on technological or scientific innovations. For the past four years, I received weekly job alerts and, anecdotally, I can say that the expectations, clarity and keywords of the ad have improved significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;analytics-podcasts&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analytics Podcasts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of really good analytics podcasts has grown significantly, to the point I can barely keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not So Standard Deviation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Data Skeptic Podcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partially Derivative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O’Reilly Data Show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking Machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not So Standard Deviations and O’Reilly Data Show are great detox if you are subject to a considerable amount of timeshare-sque-like products and hyperbolic claims by vendors or consultants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Common Mistake Data Analysts Make and How to Avoid It</title>
      <link>/post/one-common-mistake-data-analysts-make-and-how-to-avoid-it.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/one-common-mistake-data-analysts-make-and-how-to-avoid-it.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One common mistake inexperienced analyst do in analysing data is that of &lt;strong&gt;assigning a special role to time&lt;/strong&gt;. In my line of work, I see this a lot. Signs of &lt;em&gt;chronophrenia&lt;/em&gt;, a term I just made up, are the unusual focus on calendar time: from line plots of multiple variables on the y-axis against time on the x-axis, to frequencies or averages by some meaningful time cut-off: monthly, quarterly, yearly and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, I think there are plenty of scenarios when looking at time makes perfect sense and both the statistical, engineering and econometric literature continue to make substantial contributions to this area (I can think of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Change_detection&#34;&gt;change point detection&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalman_filter&#34;&gt;Kalman filters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springer.com/cda/content/document/cda_downloaddocument/9780387772370-c1.pdf?SGWID=0-0-45-771009-p173891512&#34;&gt;Bayesian/Dynamic time series&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often the analyst attempts to visually assess whether a &lt;strong&gt;shift in time exists&lt;/strong&gt;. The hope is that the shift can be tied to a special cause known to the analyst (for instance a change that was introduced at known point in time) and that this would represent evidence in favour or against a hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of drawbacks with this approach. Here I will list a few common ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we know whether a change in time is due to some special cause that happens at a know time, or whether is due to normal variation? In these settings SPC is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time does not possess magical properties: in most fields, seldom is time on the causal pathway. In other words, time does not cause much. Ok, there are some exceptions, however, at best, time is a proxy measure for something we are unable to measure. Think about it: how many times can we think of time having caused something? Death? Not really: trauma, or the inability of cells to reproduce reliably are some of the underlying causes. An old engine breaking down? Think fatigue, structural failure, wear and tear. Changing jobs? Think of complex social issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once you do fully understand a process, time plays no role (Cleves et al.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we introduce some change at a known point in time. The analyst proceeds to compare, often visually, whether a slope or a shift change occurs. The approach is limited unless we can somehow freeze everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To an untrained analyst, time is an open invitation to slice and dice the data until some interesting results are found: we will always find a reason for looking at things daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly, yearly. These are in fact, meaningful measures to a lot of businesses. Eventually, you are guaranteed to find something interesting or even significant. But it does not mean it’s true. But wait! Don’t take my word for it! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tylervigen.com/spurious-correlations&#34;&gt;Tyler Vigen&lt;/a&gt; assembled a very humorous collection of &lt;strong&gt;spurious correlations&lt;/strong&gt;. Vigen had enough material to fill a whole book. You don’t have to buy his book, though I would encourage you to do so. Some are available on Vigen’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualization pioneer Edward Tufte has a very effective visual demonstration on &lt;strong&gt;streak-guessing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;over-narrative&lt;/strong&gt; around time (here, adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0001OR&#34;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;). On the top figure we see the actual win-loss record. At the bottom, notice what happens when we randomize the order on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;winning_streak_1.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2009 Boston Red Sox win-loss record: when 4 or more wins occurs one after the other, the series is drawn in red. The causal attribution of win or loss streaks result in over-narratives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;winning_streak_2.png&#34; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not so fast: 3 randomized samples from the same data. There is little evidence for a causal mechanism of win or loss streaks that in the original series resulted in over-narratives. The invisible hand of chance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, enough about ranting against time. Let me play devil’s advocate and list some arguments in favour of time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we do not understand a process, time is often a good proxy for something we are unable to measure. We should try to smooth time to detect trends. I’m a fan of LOESS for its flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survival analysis (time to event analysis) is mostly concerned with the rate at which things are moving. Is a certain group reaching an event faster than another group? Survival analysis can effectively deal with survivorship bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we introduce a change at a given time point, there are methods that try to deal with it, such as interrupted time series or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Change_detection&#34;&gt;change point detection&lt;/a&gt; (these can go by different names). For an overview, see Kontopantelis. Change point detection is an active area of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are embarking on an analysis, don’t jump on time as your first go-to measure. Think carefully about the problem and try first to identify all factors that may affect a response of interest. Explore those first, plot them against the response, plot them against each other. Try to learn as much about your problem without recurring to time immediately. When you do look at time, remember there are challenges unique to times that complicates things (autocorrelation and censoring to name a couple).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: “&lt;em&gt;Once you do fully understand a process, time plays no role&lt;/em&gt;” … or almost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Embrace a New Identity?</title>
      <link>/post/time-to-embrace-a-new-identity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-to-embrace-a-new-identity.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssc.ca/en/vol-283-august-2014&#34;&gt;SSC Liason&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://magazine.amstat.org/blog/2014/10/01/statview-oct14/&#34;&gt;Amstat News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no question in my mind that statisticians are crossing a sea of changes. As a profession, we have made high-quality contributions to many fields over the past decades, with our engagement being perfectly epitomized in the recent book Statistics in Action: A Canadian Outlook. However, one cannot help but notice the recent trends (and hype) in the closely aligned—and somewhat vaguely defined—fields of analytics, Big Data, data science, and machine learning and wonder if our current model will continue to do well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a statistician, I am concerned. As a professional who recently migrated from the cancer research “sandbox” to the energy industry “sandbox,” I am facing numerous challenges associated with poor statistical literacy and the burden of the image problem we suffer from, which was so well captured by Brian Everitt in his book, Chance Rules: An Informal Guide to Probability, Risk, and Statistics: “[Statistics] conjures either a near-sighted character amassing volumes of figures about cricketers’ bowling and batting averages […] or a government civil servant compiling massive tables of figures” Hype aside, we are seeing a distortion of our field, the reinvention of many concepts, and the sad disregard of our contributions—often by those who do not analyze data professionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I happen to believe that many of our members and colleagues are insulated from what goes on outside of their fields, we may not fully understand the repercussions these events can have on our future. Hence, I feel compelled to list a few examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, consider the consulting firm McKinsey &amp;amp; Company, which wrote a report on Big Data in 2011. On Page 28, they list the techniques to analyze Big Data as mostly coming from the field of machine learning. However, I count at least 11 techniques that were developed in the field of statistics. On Page 30, regression, predictive modeling, and statistics are separate entities. And that’s not all. On Page 47, the authors list the new R&amp;amp;D opportunity in health care as “analyzing clinical trials data.” Does this imply we have not been analyzing clinical trials in the past? Now, to put this into perspective, consider how influential and trusted McKinsey is. Add the low statistical literacy of most organizations and we have a problem: Treating this field as novel ignores nearly 300 years of statistical history, and most people looking into Big Data won’t realize that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the machine learning attitude toward statistics is worrisome. All too often, we observe bright computer scientists who can pick up computational aspects of our work, yet rarely possess the solid statistical foundations needed to properly tackle the problem—from poor research methods to ignoring uncertainty. In a guest blog post on FierceBigData, ASA Executive Director Ronald Wasserstein wrote, “Are the data collected in a way that introduces bias? Are there missing or incomplete data? Are there different kinds of data? Statisticians not only know how to ask the right questions, but may have practical solutions already available.” There are plenty of examples of this attitude, especially on the popular forum Cross Validated. In turn, this leads to provocative articles such as “The Death of the Statistician” and “Is Data Science the End of Statistics? A Discussion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, many things are being reinvented. Bradley Efron once said, “Statistics is the science of learning from experience. Those who ignore statistics are condemned to reinvent it.” According to Wikipedia, logistic regression is a classifier. More recently, Hadley Wickham noticed how nearly 50 years of statistical smoothing literature has had little effect on information visualization, which had to reinvent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth, as Randy Bartlett explains in A Practitioner’s Guide to Business Analytics, making data analysis software more user-friendly has opened the flood gates holding back statistical malfeasances. The desire to simplify tools, methods, and solutions for use by business users has led to what some people refer to as a culture of “buttonology.” Frank Harrell had this to say: “What I most fear is that statistics wasn’t respected enough before the machine learning field went viral, and things have just gone from bad to worse. The ready availability of software has hurt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifth, false novelty is feeding reinvention. Consider Terry Speed’s talk on Big Data, for instance, in which he gave a memorable example. A University of California alumni magazine article on Big Data showed an empty row for statistics. Economics, chemistry, marketing, computer science? All there. Statistics? Nope. And to add insult to injury, they have not forgotten it; it’s simply empty, as if statistics contributed nothing. I echo what Jeff Leek wrote on his Simply Statistics blog: This “shows a fundamental disrespect for applied statisticians who have developed serious expertise in a range of scientific disciplines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent report on the future of the statistical sciences says, “Statisticians, with some prominent exceptions, also have been unwilling or unable to communicate to the rest of the world the value (and excitement) of their work.” This sentence hints at the consequences we may face if we do not act quickly: We may never have existed in the eyes of many and our contributions may be reinvented and re-packaged in a different field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the report confirms challenges we have never faced in the past: “Undoubtedly the greatest challenge and opportunity that confronts today’s statisticians is the rise of Big Data.” While some think these trends will “eventually fade,” as they did in the data mining movement of the ’90s, I believe there is too much economic interest for it to simply fade away. If the numbers of analytics software and languages are any indication of things to come, this movement is hardly going to fade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that despite the misguided direction and pitfalls, the focus and attention on Big Data (or data science) is mostly a good thing. Sure, Big Data is not going to change those organizations and research institutions that have been doing this work for decades. However, it will inevitably bring a more evidence-based approach to the way companies do business and the government makes policies. This progress, however, may come at a price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical certification is largely unrecognized outside academic and research institutions. I suspect this was meant to protect us from the very improvised statisticians who contributed to the bad image. It may have worked, if things stayed the same. I think we are falling victim to the complacency of our own culture. Perhaps, ASA Past President Robert Rodriguez saw this coming when he suggested we use the big tent approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing nothing and hoping problems will fade away is not a good strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, this is going to hurt us because we cannot properly assert our knowledge and contributions against parallel fields with a much more rapid mechanism of spreading new ideas (e.g., conference proceedings are typical in CS/ML vs. peer-review in statistics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, our lack of notoriety in other fields may deprive our departments and professors of the needed funding and recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, we have been unable or unwilling to prepare the next generation of applied statisticians for a work place that might change substantially. At present, statistics departments are reluctant to incorporate feedback from applied statisticians in the field. Applied statisticians must finish their basic training after graduate school. )Fourth, a multitude of certifications are now being established to monetize on the recent data movement. Should we not be at the forefront of this? Shouldn’t our certifications be the highest regarded owing to our nearly 300-year history? INFORMS (an operation research organization) is aggressively pushing their certification, CAP, which is establishing itself as the certification for analytics. A quick scan of its content reveals it covers a blend of data management and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways we can become more engaged. At a minimum, acknowledging and talking about these issues is a first step. Here are a few ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider being active on social media. There are numerous venues to show the rest of the world the value and excitement of our work: Stack Exchange, LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook, Quora, and the many fora specific to statistical software packages are some of the most obvious choices. I am part of a team founding About Data Analysis (ADA), a new LinkedIn discussion group specific to data analysis issues. Consider stepping outside of your comfort zone. For example, many of the methods we commonly use are now being used in other fields (e.g., survival analysis in marketing). Why not speak at conferences outside your sandbox to those who are starting to use the very methods we have mastered? Consider making some of your work openly available. Write a blog or an open-access paper. If a paper was not accepted at a journal, why not make it freely available? If you teach, consider approaching your department about making video tutorials. Look at the work of Jeff Leek and Roger Peng for examples. If you have videos of your conference presentation, make them available. As a profession, we should explore diversifying our certifications programs or joining forces with similar and reputable professional organizations. As a profession, we need to have the courage to look outside the wall that has so far protected us from unscrupulous intruders. As Randy Bartlett wrote in Amstat News, “[T]o differentiate our value proposition, we must be involved.” We need to involve ourselves with other parallel fields, learn about their problems, and share existing solutions. This does not mean lowering our standards for rigorous results. We cannot defend our profession and retain our current customers by building walls meant to keep the barbarians out. We need to empower our applied statisticians with certification and more applied training. Furthermore, we need to build bridges to support their entrance into other fields.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
